Shri Ganesha Puja, Cabella Ligure, 22 September 2001
格涅沙崇拜 意大利卡贝拉 2001年9月22日
Today we have assembled here
今天我们聚集一起
to worship Shri Ganesha.
崇拜神圣的格涅沙
Shri Ganesha who is the Lord of Innocence.
格涅沙是纯真之主，
He is the ocean of innocence.
祂是纯真的海洋。
And though’ he is
虽然祂只是
such a young, little boy,
年轻的小男孩，
he can fight the whole world,
但祂能对抗整个世界，
he can destroy all the negativity.
祂能毁灭所有负面力量，
That’s the sign of innocence.
这是纯真的记号。
There have been stories
自古以来有众多故事
that children who have fallen from a very great height
叙述小孩被害仍能
were completely saved, nothing happened to them.
完全得救，安全无恙。
Their innocence is such a powerful thing
纯真是很有力量的
It has all the wisdom of the world,
纯真力拥有世间的智慧
all the understanding of the world;
及对世界的洞悉。
and anybody who tries to harm the innocence,
任何人想伤害纯真的本质，
the world, the whole world –
全世界的人，
which may not have cared so much for innocence,
不论他们是否曾十分关注
might not have worshiped innocence so much –
或尊崇纯真的本质，
but they all stand, stand up against
都会站出来
anybody who tries to harm the innocence.
对付伤害纯真的人。
You can see in your own lives
你可从你生活周遭看到，
around you,  anybody tries to trouble children –
任何人若想苦待小孩，
all of the them, whatever they are,
所有人，
whatever they are coming from,
不论他们来自何方，
whatever maybe their nationality,
不论他们的国籍，
they all jump, all jump to control
他们统统都会站出来
and to safeguard that child.
去保护那小孩。
What is it?
这是什么？
What is it within us that makes us so very conscious
有什么在我们里面使我们意识到
to protect the innocence?
要去保护纯真？
It’s really a shame,
这对我们是
a great shame for us,
如何的侮辱，
when we find in this world that innocence is under attack.
若我们发现纯真正在受攻击。
Anything else can be tolerated.
什么都可以忍受，
Innocent people who have done nothing wrong,
但若纯真的人，没有做错什么，
those who have no malice,
也没有半点邪恶，
who are living like little children, I should say,
生活如小孩般纯真，
if they are attacked by anyone –
若他们受伤害，
not that the whole world reacts to that –
即使没有引起全世界的关注，
but everyone of them cannot bear
我们每一个人都不能
any innocent person or ‘innocent being’ being harmed.
忍受他们受伤害。
We don’t realise that within us
我们没有察觉到在我们里面
there is the ocean of love
有对孩子的爱的海洋
and ocean of understanding for children.
及洞悉力的海洋，
Why? Why should it be?
为什么？为什么是这样？
Why should we feel like that, especially for children?
为什么我们尤其对小孩、
Especially for innocence?
尤其对纯真会有这样的感受？
There are people who are always attacking innocent people,
事实上还有人不断攻击纯真的人、
innocent children, there are.
纯真的小孩，
But no-one wants to support them.
但没有人会支持他们。
No-one thinks that it’s proper to ill-treat children.
没有人会认为恶待小孩是恰当的。
And those who have done this have to suffer.
这样做的人必会受苦，
They all suffer as a reaction.
他们必然会得到受苦的回报。
What is it within us
在我们里面的
that creates that reaction, that tremendous reaction,
是什么能产生这反应，去对付破坏
against innocence?
纯真的人？
For example if there is a regular war,
举例说，若有一场平常的战争，
and if there are people fighting;
人们对作战的人
in a regular war, they don’t have much sympathy.
不会有太大的同情心。
In the world also, they say “Alright,
人们或会说：
they are of that understanding, they are of that kind of a thing”.
「他们是如此，他们都是同一群人。」
The greatest sympathy comes when innocence is being challenged.
但最大的同情心会因为纯真 受肆虐而来。
That’s what human beings have.
这便是人类的特质。
Within themselves they have the power, power of Shri Ganesha,
在人类里面有格涅沙的力量，
which gives you that feeling,
给予人们感受、
that capacity, that understanding
量度及洞悉力
that you have to protect innocent,
去保护
innocent children, innocent people.
纯真的小孩、纯真的人。
And the whole world can rise against all such people
全世界都会出来对付
who are trying to kill the innocent.
杀害纯真的人，
There cannot be any doubt.
这毋庸置疑。
If they cannot oppose such an attack,
若他们不去反对及批评那些
or criticise such a thing,
攻击纯真的人，
then they are not yet human beings, I would say.
他们并不算是人。
The highest personality can sacrifice anything
人类最高的品格能使他牺牲一切，
and can give up anything,
舍弃一切，
but they cannot give up the feeling
但他们不能放弃
they have for innocence.
维护纯真的感情，
It’s very remarkable. We don’t realise
这十分显明。我们没有察觉到
how much there is this ocean of protection and love
对纯真的人的爱及保护的
for the innocent.
海洋有多大。
What attracts the greatest strength is when we see
什么会引发最大的力量， 就是正当我们看见
an innocent person, innocent children, are under attack.
纯真的人，纯真的小孩受到攻击。
That’s the beauty of human beings.
这便是人类美丽之处。
Of course there are many human beings who can be cruel,
当然，有很多人是残酷的，
who are, I would say, call them devils – maybe, maybe.
可以称得上是恶魔，
But when it comes to children,
但若是面对孩子
and to innocent people,
及纯真的人，
everyone feels his responsibility.
每个人都感受到他们的责任。
It’s difficult for normal human beings to be innocent
一般人很难变得纯真，
because they have a kind of an understanding
因为他们自以为
that they are something great,
十分了不起，
that they understand everything, that they can analyse everything,
自以为明白一切，能分析一切。
and they could be crooks, they could be aggressive,
他们可以成为罪犯，宰制别人
they could be troublesome, they could be anything –
或充满烦恼的人，
and they can give explanation for that, doesn’t matter –
他们都可以为此找出任何理由，
but still, on the whole, they can never be respected
但他们所做的
and they can never be honoured
却永不会受到尊敬
for the thing they are doing.
或推崇。
For us, the Sahaja Yogis,
对霎哈嘉瑜伽士来说，
the Sahaj culture is to respect your innocence.
霎哈嘉文化就是要尊敬你的纯真。
You might feel a little bit cheated,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士或会感到受骗，
you might feel a little bit dominated,
被牵制或
you might feel a little bit disgraced,
受无礼对待，
but Sahaja Yogi have to be innocent.
但他们一定要保持纯真，
Because with them lies the power of Shri Ganesha.
因为在他们里面有神圣的格涅沙力量。
They should not feel dejected
他们不应感到被遗弃，
if they are being used, insulted,
即使他们曾被人利用、被人侮辱、
tortured, dominated, it’s alright.
被人虐待、被人牵制。这不成问题。
They should not try to destroy
他们不应尝试去毁灭
the innocence of other people, of anyone.
别人的纯真，
Automatically it will work. You will be amazed
事情自然会成就出来。
that when innocence is challenged,
你会稀奇若纯真被侵害，
all the goodness of the world comes to the rescue of that.
世界一切美善都要到来拯救。
An example of this is the recent war, so-called war, of America.
最近在美国的袭击，
Where innocent people – they had done nothing wrong
便是无辜的人
– have been tortured,have been killed.
受到虐待、杀害的例子。
At that time, all over the world,
在此时，全世界
it’s a big support for them.
都引来巨大的支持。
Every country, whether it believes in those people or not,
不论宗教及国籍，
is anxious to look after
全世界都想知道
those who have done this crime.
谁做此罪行。
they may not be belonging to the same country,
他们不是来自同一宗教、同一国家，
they may not be belonging to the same crimes,
或犯下同一罪行，
but at this moment, who does not take the side of the innocence
但当此时，那些没有靠在纯真那边的人
will be singled out and will be destroyed – no doubt about it.
都会被孤立，被毁灭，无须置疑。
Once and for all they will learn a lesson
这一次，他们会受到教训，
that ‘you cannot attack innocent people’.
他们不应攻击纯真无辜的人。
I have told you, in Sahaja Yoga,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽内，
we should not ever be annoyed with out children.
我们不应对小孩子感到厌烦。
We should not, in no way punish them.
我们不应该以任何方式惩罚他们。
Our main achievement
我们最重要的是
should be that loving attention for children.
要对小孩有爱的关注，
All over the world, whether he belongs
不论是世界任何角落，
to your family or to some other family,
不论他是否你的小孩或人家的小孩，
or has some sort of
或他们对你
detached attention with you,
有否理睬。
still because he’s a child, he’s innocent,
因为他是小孩，他是纯真
the innocence within itself, your own innocence,
──那内在的纯真──你自己的纯真
will try to protect.
会去保护小孩。
It’s very surprising how people take to sacrificing their lives
我们十分惊叹人们面对纯真
when it comes to the attack of innocence.
受伤害时不惜牺牲性命。
Children should never be attacked.
小孩子永远都不能受攻击，
They have their own power to protect, no doubt.
当然他们自有保护自己的力量， 无须置疑。
But you shouldn’t waste your energy on something
但你不应耗费精力在
that is extremely inauspicious,
那些不吉祥，
extremely cruel and extremely ugly.
极之残酷及丑恶的事情上。
If you cannot love children, you cannot love anything.
若你不能爱小孩， 你就什么也不能爱。
I have not come across anyone so far who says
我从来没有遇见
that they don’t love children – luckily!
自称不爱小孩的，真幸运！
But maybe some might say “We love flowers”. Why?
或许有人说：「我们爱花朵。」 「为什么？」
Why do you love flowers? Because they are innocent.
「为什么你会爱花朵？」
Because that beauty of innocence is within them.
因为花朵也同样有纯真的美丽。
You love nature – why?
你们爱大自然，为什么？
Because it is innocent.
正因为其纯真。
But the greatest innocence is seen among human beings
但是人类最伟大的纯真便是
who are Sahaja Yogis.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
It is easy to be cunning, very easy to be cunning.
变得狡猾及聪敏
It’s very easy to be clever.
很容易，
But to be wise, one should understand
但若要有智慧，人们要明白
the beauty of being innocent.
变得纯真的美丽。
Possibly one may say “Mother,
你或会说：「母亲，
one can get exploited if you are innocent”.
纯真的人容易受剥削。」
No-one can exploit an innocent person.
但其实没有人可以剥削纯真的人，
They may believe that they have done this,
他们或以为是这样，
they have been very aggressive and all that, but they cannot.
他们可以变得十分好侵略， 但实质上却不能。
It is like a rock.
这就如一块坚石
It is like a rock that is not prevailed by
这就如一块坚石不会被
any ocean of anger
忿怒的海洋
or any kind of revenge.
及任何报复的行动压倒。
It’s the rock that is being looked after
这块坚石正受
and nourished by Shri Ganesha.
格涅沙的保护、养育。
I’ve told you before also,
正如我以往曾告诉你们，
that the innocence within us never gets destroyed.
纯真在我们里面永远不会被毁灭。
Very surprising. You may be a sinner,
这十分稀奇，你或会是一个罪人，
you may be a very cruel person, you might be anything:
或是一个残酷的人，你或是任何东西，
but it does not get,
但内里的
it cannot get it.
纯真不会
After innocence.
被毁，
It is a very, very secret thing that is put in us by the Divine.
是上天放在我们里面十分隐秘的东西。
We play with our innocence very much.
我们对我们的纯真玩把戏，
We think that by behaving any way we like,
我们认为随自己喜欢行事没有问题。
“It’s alright, after all it’s my own desire, my wish”.
「没问题，毕竟这是我的欲望、 我的意愿。」
And we’ll go on, we go on all the time
故我们继续任意削弱
reducing our power, or we can say the hiding,
及隐藏我们纯真的力量，
or covering our power of innocence.
想着要去愚弄别人。
And we think that we have done a great job,
但这种狡猾性情
that we have befooled all the people by our tricky nature.
不能给你任何满足。
This tricky nature cannot give you any satisfaction.
它不能使你
It is not self-sufficient.
达到满足。
When you try to trick someone, this trick works on you,
若你愚弄别人，这把戏只在你身上回报，
it is repelled on you, and destroys your faith in innocence –
那欺诈只在你身上毁灭你对纯真的信念。
which is the greatest faith,
而纯真正是最大的信念，
the greatest help
最大的帮助，
or [UNCLEAR} the greatest power on this earth.
在大地上最大的力量。
Those people who do not respect their innocence
那些不尊重自己纯真的人，
because they think it makes you weak,
他们认为纯真会令他们变得软弱，
have not seen the power of innocence –
因为他们看不见纯真的力量，
how it works, how it acts.
它如何行动，如何发生果效，
From all over the world, it reacts.
在全世界正起作用。
But, so far, I think the human beings are not conscious of the power
但一直以来，我认为人类没有意识到
power of innocence.
纯真的力量。
But it is the highest thing to be innocent.
纯真最高尚，
And it acts
它起作用，
as if the whole understanding,
就好像一切见解，
whole working-out of the be-ing
一切作为都得到
is so beautifully achieved.
最美丽的成就。
Now you see in this world
在这世上，
what says ,what people remember, what is respected.
什么会受人纪念及尊敬？
It is respected the high ideals.
就是那些活出崇高理想的人，
But if you see to the subtle side of these high ideals of people
就是那些美好品格的人
have led a very, very beautiful life of very good character,
活出的美丽生命。
of very good nature’
美丽生命。
– all these people may have been harmed
所有这些人都曾受伤害，
may have been killed –
或被杀害，
but because of their innocence they shine,
但由于纯真，
and shine through ages.
他们的光芒历世闪耀。
You can see the life of all great men like that;
你可看见所有伟大的人的生命都是这样。
they are all very simple,
他们都十分单纯，
they are not deliberating anything –
他们没有任何做作，
spontaneous they are in their behaviour, spontaneously they live.
他们行事自然，生活自然。
Nations after nations can be destroyed,
国家可以一个一个被毁灭，
but the power of innocence cannot be destroyed.
但纯真的力量不能被毁灭。
Have faith in that.
要对此有信念。
You have to have complete faith in yourself,
你们对自己要有完全的信心，
and that ‘yourself’ is nothing but innocence.
你们的真我不是什么，而是纯真。
You may say that ‘innocent people get cheated’.
你们或认为纯真的人容易受骗，
Nobody can cheat innocence,
但没有人可以欺骗纯真，
because that is something of very eternal value.
因为纯真关乎永恒的价值。
They might cheat you in money, might cheat you in something,
他们可以欺骗你金钱，骗你一些东西，
but the thing that is the most eternal is your innocence.
但不能骗去你那最永恒的纯真。
And you will be the most successful person
若你绝对的纯真，
in life when you are absolutely innocent
并好好照顾你的纯真，
and your are looking after your innocence.
你在此生中将会是最成功的人。
As I have told you, that innocence never gets destroyed.
正如我告诉你们，纯真永不会被毁灭。
It can be covered by your ill thoughts,
它可以因为你的坏思想、
by ill doing, it might be covered for the time being.
坏行为而被隐藏一段时间，
But if you can take out the clouds
但若在纯真的
away from the sky of innocence,
天空中，
the whole thing becomes so obvious
你把污云带走，
that you have won the whole world.
你便能战胜整个世界。
We can take the case of Christ. He was crucified,
我们可以基督为例，祂被人钉十字架，
he was insulted, he was tortured.
被人侮辱，被人折磨。
Those who did this, where are they?
干此事的人，他们在哪里？
Who knows them? Nobody even knows the name.
谁会理会他们？ 没有人会知道他们的名字，
Nobody is even bothered about them.
没有人愿意认识他们。
A single one person was so much used
一个单独的人
and was so much tortured.
被如此折磨，
But despite that, what has happened?
但这是怎样的一回事？
He has got the respect from the whole world.
基督被全世界纪念、
The whole world respects.
被全世界尊崇，
Nobody says that ‘Look at that, how he was crucified,
没有人着意祂如何被钉十字架。
what has he done …’ Nothing of the kind.
不是这样，
They just respect. And what do they respect? The essence,
人们只是尊崇祂。 人们尊崇什么呢？就是祂
the essence of complete innocence.
那完全纯真的本质。
They say in Sahaja Yoga that he was the incarnation of innocence.
用霎哈嘉瑜伽的话说， 祂是纯真本质的降世，
He was the incarnation of Shri Ganesha – which can be verified.
祂是神圣格涅沙的降世。 这可以验证出来。
So, when we think that in our own ventures we can do what we like,
若你以为你可以任意妄为，
and we don’t want to even remember that, we don’t want to even
不想考虑自己
consider that it’s a wrong thing to do,
是否做错，
we do not know what is ahead of us.
你们不知道在你们面前的东西。
What happened to Hitler also?
有什么降临希特勒身上？
He thought he can destroy the whole world,
他以为他可以毁灭全世界，
he can manage to kill so many people
他可以操纵杀戮众人之事，
and still he will remain a very great personality.
他以为还可以给自己高尚的人格。
They are stupid not to understand
他们都是愚蠢的人， 不明白在他们之前
who are the people really respected.
那些人才会受尊敬。
Through ages, through history, no-one like Hitler.
历世以来，没有人喜欢希特勒。
He didn’t understand if you wanted to have
他不明白若要拥有
really the power over the world,
驾御世界的能力，
and he wanted to have the reputation of a great man,
成为受尊重的人，
he should have followed the great people.
就必定要效法伟大的人。
And the great people are those who are innocent.
那些伟大的人便是纯真的人，
Their main power is innocence; take any one of them.
他们主要的能力来自纯真本质。 他们任何一个都是这样。
I don’t know how to say that this power acts,
我不知道如何述说这力量的工作，
because it acts in so many ways.
因为它以多方面发挥作用。
You can pass through historical events, so many of them,
我们可参考历史事实，有众多的记载，
and what will you find? A person who is so innocent,
我们会有什么发现？十分纯真、
simple and wise
单纯、有智慧的人
is remembered all your life.
会受人传颂。
I was a child, very small, when I was in school
我年小在学校的时候，
I used to go to the library
我曾经去过图书馆，
and read about the lives of great men
看那些伟人的故事。
who have created some great things for us.
他们为我们开创了很多伟大的事情。
So many of them.
有很多那样的人。
And I was so impressed
我很钦佩
how some of them were so simple, so child-like.
他们当中有些是十分单纯， 如小孩子般。
For example Abraham Lincoln
例如林肯，
for whom I have tremendous, tremendous respect,
我对他极之极之尊崇，
was a man tortured by his wife also.
他常受他妻子的苦待。
She said “You don’t know, you are very clumsy,
她妻子常说： 「你不知道自己十分呆板，
you don’t know how to dress up, you don’t know how to behave”.
不懂得衣着，不懂得表现自己。」
And she actually was very harsh on him, all the time torturing him.
她真的对他十分苛刻，经常折磨他。
Ultimately he was also killed.
最后他也被谋杀，
So one can say, “You see, what’s the use of being Abraham Lincoln?
有人或会说：「林肯又怎样？
Because he was killed, he was not successful.”
因为他被杀害，他不成功。」
Until today, all over the world,
直到今日全世界
people know who was Abraham Lincoln.
都知道林肯是谁，
They don’t know his wife – maybe.
但没有人知道他的妻子。
But they knew who was Abraham Lincoln, everybody.
人人都知道林肯是谁。
Clumsy man, according to her,
对于她来说，他是呆板的男子
and all sorts of degradation for him.
并且还有所有不时尚的东西。
But nobody respects her, nobody thinks anything about her.
但没有人尊敬她， 根本没有人想到她。
Who is respected today is Abraham Lincoln.
今日受到尊敬的正是林肯。
Why? ‘Actually he was murdered, he was killed,
为什么？实际上他是被谋杀的， 被杀害的，
that shows that he had no strength to survive’ –
他没有存活的力量
but he survived through ages!
但其实他历世长存！
So many years have passed, still he’s surviving.
这么多年头过去，他依然存在。
Take the case of all the great people
看所有纯真的
who have been innocent;
伟大的例子，
and that’s why they had ideals.
他们为何会有远大理想，
To them their ideals were more important than anything else,
对他们来说， 他们的理想比任何事情都重要，
even their lives. Everything was nothing.
什么东西都不算是什么， 即使是他们的生命。
Now the sense of ideals and idealism
理想、宏愿源自于
comes only from your innocence.
你们的纯真，
That’s the one which teaches you what is your ideal;
它教导你
how you should exist;
何谓理想，
what kind of a life you should lead.
你应如何生活。
It is not important that you have big authorities,
你是否拥有极大权力并不重要，
or you have a very big positions as ministers and all that.
或你是否站在首相般高位， 所有一切都不重要。
There have been so many who came and died.
很多人都是这样来了又死去。
They had so many people with ambitions
有很多人都十分具野心
and so many people who were oppressive, but where are they?
及好侵略，但他们在哪里？
Nobody’s bothered about them, nobody wants to look at them.
没有人关注他们， 没有人愿意理会他们。
If their photograph appears people close their eyes
若他们的相片出现人们眼前， 人们会闭上眼睛。
‘No, no, we don’t want to see this man’.
没有人想看见他们。
But if there’s a little boy, innocent child,
但若有一个小孩子，纯真的小孩子，
who is talking in a very innocent manner,
说话十分纯真，
the whole world admires that child.
全世界都会欣赏他。
And these great men are, really,
伟大的人便是
they are the symbols of that innocence.
纯真的象征，
Their main quality was innocence, from where the wisdom has come.
他们的主要特质是纯真， 那便是智慧的所在。
Ganesha’s main quality is his wisdom.
格涅沙的主要特质是祂的智慧。
He knew what was success, through his,
祂知道成功源于祂
I should say, innocent qualities.
纯真的特质。
Sometimes the innocent people are not even aware of their
有些纯真的人并不察觉自己的
quality of innocence.
纯真特质。
It’s very surprising how the quality of innocence
这令人惊叹纯真本质
shines through human beings who may be very ordinary,
如何透过人类发出光彩，
who may be very
那些人
who may be very simple, who may not look so intelligent and sharp,
或是十分平凡，或是十分简单， 或外表并不聪明或出色，
who may not become good diplomats, what ever it is –
或不是个外交出色的人。 无论是什么，
they are innocent! That’s were ends all the glory of human beings.
他们依然纯真， 这正是人类所有荣耀的终归。
To be innocent –
要变得纯真，
What’s the matter?
我们要做什么？
– so to be innocent, what do you do?
要变得纯真，我们要做什么？
People will say, “Mother, what do we do to be innocent?”
人们或会说：「母亲， 我们要做什么才可变得纯真？」
Firstly, you can see for yourself
首先你要看清你的
how your mind works.
脑袋运作，
What does it do? How it reacts.
它做了什么，
This is what one has to watch,
如何反应。
which I call as ‘introspection’.
这便是内省。
What sort of plans your mind takes to?
你的脑袋有什么打算？
What does it think is the best?
它认为什么是最好？
In that thinking, thought process,
在这思考的过程中，
what is the most important way to look at yourself?
什么是看清自己的最好方法？
The first and the foremost is that
首先和最主要的是
you should know how you react to someone.
你应如何向别人作出反应，
Is it an innocent reaction? Or it is a vindictive reaction.
这是否一个纯真的响应， 或只是一种掩饰？
It is very easy to see yourself,
要看清自己，十分容易，
because now you are all Sahaja Yogi.
因为你们现在都是霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
You can see for yourself how is your reaction
你可看出你对
to any aggression on you, or any kind of a
侵略行为或麻烦事的反应。
trouble coming on you. How do you react to that?
你的反应如何？
What is your behaviour?
你的行为如何？
If you are a very powerful person, then your behaviour is –
若你是十分有力量的人，你的行为
for that you are not bothered. You see for yourself its
会显得你不会受骚扰。你会看到
just a stupid thing people are doing to you.
只是那些人向你做出的愚蠢行为，
Absolutely stupid.
这是绝对愚蠢的。
And when they are doing stupid things,
他们做出愚蠢事，
why should we bother about them?
我们何必理会他们？
Why should we waste our energy about them?
我们为何为此要浪费自己的精力？
It comes to a point where their stupidity is found out,
他们的愚蠢终有一刻令别人知识，
in such a manner that all their lives and afterwards
最终只会受人
they are treated with contempt.
藐视，
People don’t even want to take their names,
人们不想提及他们的名字，
they don’t want to have their photographs,
不想有他们的相片，
they don’t want to have anything to do with them.
不想和他们有什么关系。
At this time, at such a juncture,
那些歪曲、
what happens is the people who are crooks,
不纯真，
who are not innocent, who are against innocence,
甚至对抗纯真的人
they start following them because it suits them better.
会跟随他们，因为这更适合他们。
It suits them to be aggressive, to be cunning
他们喜欢好侵略
and that’s how a new group is formed –
及诡诈，
which we can call ‘a satanic group’.
故此撒旦组织会形成，
And this satanic group also cannot do anything,
但他们不能对
anything whatsoever, to an innocent personality.
赋有纯真个性的人作什么。
There is a Sanskrit sloka like that –
梵文的诗句有云
‘It cannot be killed by any weapon’.
灵魂不能被任何武器杀伤；
Nainam dahanti pavaka – ‘No fire can burn it’.
没有火可把它毁掉；
Marutha is the air, or we can call it wind,
Marutha 意即空、气或风，
‘Wind cannot also suck it’,
风不能把它吸走，
it is above all the nature, which is trying to destroy.
这是高出一切大自然的毁灭力量。
But you will be amazed that nature understands.
大自然明白一切，
I told you, nature is innocent.
正因它纯真。
It understands and it acts
它会在适当的时机
at the right moment, against the person who is aggressive,
对付好宰制的人，
who is trying to malign
他们尝试去欺负
or trouble an innocent person.
纯真的人。
In this way we should know that we have to worship our innocence.
我们应知道我们要尊崇纯真本质。
I know sometimes one feels
我知道有人
that you are dominated because of that.
或会感到因他的纯真而被宰制。
Sometimes one feels sad that  ‘Why you are put to this kind
有时会感到因受了别人如此
of a treatment by others’.
对待而难过。
All kinds of things come to your mind.
所有这些东西都进入你的思想。
But if you worship your innocence,
但若你尊崇你的纯真，
then you will be always a happy person,
你会常常是个快乐的人，
always a kind person, always be humble person.
常常是个仁慈的人， 常常是个谦虚的人。
So, one has to be careful.
故此你们要小心，
You are your own destroyer!
你是你自己的毁灭者，
You are the one who kills, you see
你可以杀害你自己。你看
What do you say to it?
你是怎么看待的呢？
Hitler destroyed himself; who has destroyed him?
我们如何评论希特勒？谁人毁灭他？ 正是希特勒毁灭自己。
I mean in any way, everybody has to die so he would have been dead.
每个人终归都有一死， 故他也不例外会死，
But who has destroyed it forever is himself.
但谁人把他永久的毁灭？ 正是他自己。
So, you kill yourself –
你可杀害自己，
through this you can save yourself
但同样透过纯真，
and become very glorified if you are innocent.
你可拯救你自己，并满有光荣。
Have faith in the power of innocence.
你们要对纯真的力量有信心。
What is important is, how you show in your own life
重要的是在你的生命中 如何表现纯真的力量，
the power of innocence, how you behave towards each other,
你们之间如何互相对待，
and that is what is what, is what I call ‘the love’.
这便是我所说的爱。
You cannot be compassionate unless and until
你不能变得慈悲，
you have this attitude towards yourself.
除非你对自己有这态度，
You cannot be kind. Temporarily you might feel this,
否则你不能变得仁慈，对你而言， 仁慈只是短暂的感受。
but a permanently compassionate temperament comes
但是永远慈悲的性情是
only through the permanent flowing of innocence
来自那人的性格上有纯真
through your character.
的本性永恒地流通，
It’s such a transparent thing in a human being
它隐透于人类之中
and that it sustains, it overpowers all other things,
并育养人类，它比什么力量都强，
leave alone the time – thousands of years people will not forget
千年以后，人们不会忘记你们，
you the Sahaja Yogi, if you show your valour
那霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
and your strength of your innocence.
若你们表现你们的勇气及纯真的力量。
I’m sorry for today’s programme being so late,
很抱歉，今日的聚会延迟了。
but you know I was ready to come
但你们知道我已准备好出来，
but the marriages are becoming the main function now.
但那婚姻选配已成为今日的主要项目。
Because it came so late,
由于那选配迟了，
that till the last minute we were deciding about marriages.
我们直到最后一分钟仍考虑那婚姻安排。
But I am telling you this is the last time. Next time we’ll stop it.
但我要告诉你们这是最后一次， 下一次我们要停止了。
You must send your applications
你们要最迟八天前把申请表寄来
at least eight days before, and for Ganapatipule it is two weeks.
若是在格纳帕提普蕾 (Ganapatipuli) 要在两星期前。
Otherwise – there are only twenty-four hours in a day,
我们一天只有二十四小时，
and you cannot increase those!
不能再增加。
Now there is one humble request I have to make,
我有一个恳请，
that if you want to settle your marriage,
若你想有美好的婚姻安排，
then please do it in a way that I can have time to see.
便要让我有充足时间去察看，
Otherwise I’ll leave it to others to decide.
否则我会让其他人去决定。
If you like, it can be done.
若你喜欢是如此，也可以是这样。
So a simple thing is this to understand,
最简单不过的是
that marriage is a very important thing.
要明白婚姻是十分重要的事情，
You can create innocent children if you are married.
你们可以创造纯真的小孩子， 若你们成婚。
But if you behave in this manner, little, little responsible –
但若你们的行为如此，责任感太少，
so I have to request you to understand the value of time.
故我要求你们明白时间的价值，
Because from next time I can assure you we cannot have marriages
因为下一次我不会为你们作婚姻安排，
if you send your applications so late.
若你们太迟递交申请表。
It should be within one week’s time,
这最少要在一个星期前，
I hope you’ll understand that.
我希望你们明白。
Thank you very much.
谢谢